本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
美剧字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：猫妖柒   Olivia_xuxu   扭扭布   二摆舞   ViceVersa   和小蟹
时间轴：GWN    暮暮      校对：狂舞之鹤    Olivia_xuxu
■
后期：渔夫       字幕总监制：狂舞之鹤
《远古入侵：新世界》第一季 第九集
Primeval:New World S01E09
老兄  你还好吧
Spider, are you okay?
看看这个
Check this.
什么鬼玩意儿
What the hell!
我一定要找到它  太神奇了
I got go find it. Damn it!
就这样  我去找  你拿着视频
Okay, I'll go find it., you got the vidoe out there.
让大家看到你望着天空发呆
I'm not sure it's good for company morale
对公司的士气没好处吧
for people to see you staring into space.
更别说你自己了
Not to mention your morale.
我没事
I'm doing okay.
那公司呢
And the company?
我想如果未来三个月  我能全力
Well, I think I can stave off bankruptcy
研发新产品  扩展销售渠道
if I devote myself full-time for the next three months
公司还是可以避免破产的
to updated product and aggressive sales calls.
你的热情还真挺鼓舞人心的
Well, your enthusiasm is inspiring.
谢谢
Thanks.
事实我其实对鼓舞士气一点不在行
Truth is, I'm not much of a cheerleader.
那是安吉的长处
That was always Ange.
没她在身边帮忙感觉真怪
Doing this without her just feels weird.
你和她谈过了吗
Have you talked to her at all?
她不会回来的  如果你想问的话
She's not coming back, if that's your question.
你想找人代替她吗
Do you have a plan to replace her?
你知道我的意思
You know what I mean.
她的工作
The job.
明白  我收到了一些简历
Yeah, I'm getting resumes.
可任何一个有头脑能接手她工作的人
But anyone smart enough to do that job
都会聪明到能发现
will be smart enough to find out that
旧的化学燃料库已经成了
that old chem bunker has been converted
我的恐龙狩猎队总部了
into the headquarters of my dinosaur-hunting team.
这样只会让我们更具吸引力
Well, that just makes us sound glamorous.
你跟迈可联系过吗
Have you called Mac?
没有
No.
过段时间再说吧
I'm giving it some time.
多久
How much?
我不知道
I don't know.
我是说  我又能做什么
I mean, what am I supposed to do?
给他打电话吗
Give him a call?
给他留言解释
Leave him a voice mail
我们之所以会成为朋友的真正原因
explaining that the real reason we're friends
是在某个平行的时空
is that because in some alternate reality,
他穿越回去救了我的命吗
he went back in time and saved my life?
我想他被冻在地下室的身体
I think his frozen body in the basement
才是最难解释的部分吧
is actually the harder part to explain.
你会看成本报表吗
Do you know anything about cost reports?
完全看不懂
Not a damn thing.
伙计们
Hey, guys?
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
恐龙出现了
A dinosaur problem?
三角龙算吗
A triceratops?
出现在西温哥华呢
In west van?
成本报表的事看来得推迟了
Looks like the cost reports will have to wait.
等等  你怎么知道是哪种恐龙
Wait, how do you know what kind of dinosaur?
转给他人  分享此链接
看到点击量了吗
Did you notice the hit count?
我刚上来的时候还不到九千
When I first came upstairs, it was under 9,000.
现在超过三万五千次了
Now it's over 35,000.
不少人在关注啊
That's a lot of eyeballs.
会不会是恶搞呢
No chance it's a hoax?
不  我很清楚原创动画社区
No, I'm pretty plugged in to the homebrew animation community.
这个不是假的
This isn't a fake.
视频名称"骇人真恐龙"
This is a "Freaking' real dino."
是今天拍的吗
And it was taken today?
几个小时之前
A couple of hours ago.
我装了个数据包嗅探器
I've got a sniffer
监控所有和恐龙有关的信息
running on all dino stuff.
早些时候发现了它
I caught it early.
数以千计的人点击了这个恐龙视频
So a few thousand people click on a dinosaur video,
点击量介于"弹钢琴的猫"
in between piano-playing cat
和"本周美颜植物"之间
and faceplant-of-the-week.
没人会当真的
No one'll take it seriously.
我不担心新加坡的网友
I'm not worried about some guy in Singapore
把视频推给自己的朋友
tweeting it to his friends.
我担心的是有本地人认出这个滑板场
I'm worried about locals recognizing that skate park
然后跑去一看究竟
and going out there to check it out.
你能删掉这个视频吗
Can you take this down?
不费功夫  我在删了
Yeah, with a little effort. I mean, I'm on it.
我去拿装备
I'll grab the gear.
我们过去看看
Let's get out there.
异常点探测器怎么样了
What's the status on the anomaly detector?
大概还要修半天的时间才能运作
Oh, we're still 12 hours away from operational.
有什么我可以帮忙的吗
Any way I can help?
没有
No.
我们能搞定
We'll be okay.
我们一到那附近之后
Once we're in the general vicinity,
这个便携探测器会带我们找到具体方位
the handheld can get us the rest of the way.
迈可呢  要打电话给他吗
What about Mac? Are we going to call him?
不用
No.
让他静一静吧
Let's leave him alone.
好吧
Okay.
不知道这些能不能对付一只成年三角龙
Not sure how much these'll do against a full-grown triceratops.
它比我们之前所见的史前生物都巨大
This is bigger than anything we've been up against before.
这话安慰人
That's comforting.
它是被捕食的动物
It's a prey animal.
食草生物
A herbivore.
较好的情况是  如果它能找到安全的地方
There's a good case that it'll just den down,
它就会藏起来
if it can find a safe spot.
一个有水有食物的地方
Somewhere with edible plants and water.
只要它不向我吐有致幻蘑菇成分的口水
Just so long as it doesn't spew magic mushrooms all over me,
就行了
I'm good.
就是那儿
There.
就在棒球场那边
Just past the baseball diamond.
它当时就在那儿
That's where it was.
或许我们可以追踪到它的踪迹
Maybe we can pick up its trail.
知道是谁拍的视频了
I think we know who shot the footage.
你还好吗
You all right?
挺好
I'm good, man.
你就是那个拍"骇人真恐龙"的人吧
You're the freakin' real dino guys, right?
是啊  很酷吧
Yeah, cool, huh?
要我在你衣服上签名吗
Want me to sign your shirt?
你们知道它朝哪个方向去了吗
You guys know which way it went?
我想去追它  但它跑了
I tried going after it, but it was gone.
埃文
Evan...
托比
Hey, Toby.
来了两家新闻报道组
Two news crews just showed up.
事情越来越麻烦了
This thing's getting out of hand.
越来越麻烦是什么意思
What do you mean "Getting"?
这段视频已经被数家网站转载
The video is mirrored on over a dozen different websites.
"骇人真恐龙"在推特上疯传
"Freaking real dino" is trending on twitter.
我总不能把整个网络和当地新闻都封锁吧
I can't shut down the whole internet and the local news.
好吧
Okay, um...
联系肯・利兹  看他能不能帮上忙
Call Ken Leeds. See if he can help.
收到
Copy that.
你好  肯・利兹在吗
Hi, yeah, can I speak with Ken Leeds?
什么事情
What is it regarding?
告诉他出了点状况  我需要他的帮助
Uh, tell him that I need help containing a situation.
是什么状况
What is the nature of the situation?
我能直接和他谈吗  事情挺敏感
Can I just talk to him? This is sensitive.
这里处理的事情都很敏感
All matters that this office handles are sensitive.
你得说具体一点
You'll have to be more specific.
你是哪位
Who are you?
我是丽莎・梅利维斯准尉
I'm warrant officer Lisa Merriweather.
中尉的新助手
I'm the lieutenant's new assistant.
行  很好
Oh, okay, great.
那就做好助手的本分让我跟他谈谈
So assist him and let him speak with me.
你不说清楚  我不予通报
Not until you tell me what it's regarding.
好吧
Fine!
有电视台记者要去采访
A TV crew is about to interview people
目击了活体三角龙的人
who have seen a live triceratops
好做专题报道
for a special report on the news
在今晚播出
tonight.
现在我能和他通话了吗
Now can I speak with him?
你的话我会转达给他的
I'll be sure he gets your message.
那家伙个头庞大
That thing is so big,
居然到现在还没人发现它
I'm surprised no one's found it yet.
你说得对
You're right.
它个头的确很大
It's huge.
在那边
There.
它从这边来的
It came this way.
磁力计在这个方向上有波动
I'm getting a reading from this direction.
这下可好  那边人群涌动我们都还不知所措
Great. We've left the crowd behind,
现在又要擅闯私人领地了
and now we're trespassing.
为什么有人会觉得需要
Why is it that some people feel they need
一千平米大的私人地盘呢
10,000 square feet of personal space?
首先这附近住着不少高科技人才
Well, a lot of tech guys live in this area.
而且我们原本也不乐于交际
We're not the most sociable bunch to begin with.
围栏是从里面被推倒的
This is pushed outward.
这里看来
It looks like there are tracks here
有来回走动过的痕迹
going back and forth.
也许主人去度假了
Well, maybe they're on vacation.
我们几时这么走运了
When do we ever get that lucky?
异常点应该就在拱门那边
The anomaly should be just past that arch somewhere.
这是哪门子的地址啊
What kind of address is that?
"阿尔法"
"Alpha."
希腊语的第一个字母
The first letter of the Greek alphabet.
这可不算是地址  除非这里的主人
That's not an address, unless the guy who lives here
是想郑重声明他在同类中
is trying to make a serious statement
至高无上的地位
about his position in the pack,
如此说来  他每天早上
in which case, peeing on the door
在门口尿一泡岂非更省事
every morning might be quicker.
阿尔法是一切表示光谱精细结构常数的标志
It's the symbol for the fine structure constant of the universe,
可出现在这里就不是好事了
and that right there is bad news.
为什么
Why?
这房子是霍华德・凯纳恩的
This place belongs to Howard Kanan.
那家伙是个传奇人物
Guy's a legend.
在移动通信和医学成像
Key patents in mobile communications,
以及油田遥感技术领域
medical imaging,
拥有核心专利
remote oil-field sensing--
他涉足的每一个领域
Every arena he worked in,
都硕果累累
he was brilliant.
公认的天才
Certifiable genius.
天才
Genius?
比如他能明白异常点探测器工作原理吗
Like he could understand how that thing works?
我们得尽快找到那只恐龙
We've got to find that creature
在被凯纳恩发现以前把它弄走
and get it out of here before Kanan sees it.
假如他知道了  他一定想参与
If he knew, he'd want in.
你知道只要妨碍他的公司
Do you know that he buried
都被他一一击溃了吗
every single company that got in his way?
你很了解他
You know a lot about him.
是啊  我们打过交道
Yeah, we've crossed paths.
我能保住公司算是佛祖庇佑了
I'm lucky I still have my company.
埃文・克劳斯
Evan Cross!
你个鬼鬼祟祟的贼
You thieving prick.
原来你们认识
So, you two know each other.
打官司认识的
Mostly from court.
他想告我专利侵权
He tried to sue me for patent infringement,
但他无凭无据
but he didn't have a case.
我输了  不代表我错了
I lost. Doesn't mean I'm not right.
你是哪位
And, uh, you are...?
狄伦・威尔
Dylan Weir.
我什么专利都没有
I don't hold any patents.
你们怎么跑到我家来了
Why are you on my property?
观察鸟类
Bird watching.
我听说这一带有个稀有的品种
I heard there was a rare specimen out here.
喜欢在水边栖息
Likes to roost near water.
那是黑蛎鹬
Would that be the black oyster-catcher
还是长喙麻鹬呢
or the long-billed curlew?
是隐居鸫
Hermit thrush.
专业  我喜欢
You, I like. Conditionally.
你呢  克劳斯
How about you, Cross?
你是来看鸟  还是来偷鸟
You here to watch the birds or just steal them?
我觉得是时候
You know what, I think it's about time
把我们之间的误会弄个水落石出了
you and I straightened out this whole misunderstanding.
光电电路不是你首创的
You did not pioneer photonic circuitry.
是我
I did.
我哪里误会了
So which part am I misunderstanding?
是我发明的  被他剽窃了
I invented it, and he stole it.
如果你感兴趣  我可以向你证明
If you'd like, I can prove it.
他证明不了
He can't prove that.
不  我可以
Yes, I can.
进来吧
Come on in.
等等  如果你觉得你有证据
Hang on, if you think you have proof,
应该让我看个清楚
I should be the one that you show.
有事给我打电话
Call me if you need anything.
你也是
Back at you.
他怎么可能没空
How can he be busy?
除非有飞碟降落在市中心了
Unless a flying saucer has landed downtown,
我们才是磁石项目唯一的任务
we're the only thing that Project Magnet does!
好  很好  太好了
Yeah, great, awesome.
你何不再给他转达一下
Why don't you give him another message?
迈可
Mac!
你好  托比
Hey, Tobes.
我们还真是不来电啊  是吧
Wow, affection really doesn't work for us, does it?
我心里是爱你的
I love you on the inside.
埃文呢
Where's Evan?
我得跟他好好谈谈
We need to have a serious chat.
他又出去抓恐龙了
He's on another dino-hunt,
而且这回温哥华所有爱围观的都出动了
along with every other lookie-loo in Vancouver.
这么说恐龙的秘密终究纸包不住火了
So the dinosaurs are finally out of the bag?
是啊  我还得想办法
Yeah, and I have to figure out a way
把这件事遮掩过去
to put them back in the bag,
可我已经黔驴技穷了
But I don't have a bag.
利兹上尉不见人影  安吉辞职
Leeds is AWOL, Ange quit,
埃文和狄伦在外头刺激有趣
Evan and Dylan are doing the fun stuff,
我要是想不到办法解决这事
and if I don't figure out a way to stop this,
就要面对一大群人
then we're going to have a lot of people
问得我们哑口无言
asking a lot of questions that we don't want to answer.
比如"为什么我的身体在冷冻室"吗
Like, "Why my body is in a freezer?"
原谅我对你的
Forgive me if I'm having trouble
公关难题无动于衷
getting worked up about public relations,
我都不确定自己到底是死是活
but I'm not sure if I'm alive or dead.
你这是干什么
What was that?
你还活着
You're alive.
那楼下怎么还冷冻着一个我
So how can I be downstairs on ice?
拜托  你现在真的想听我讲
Oh, come on, do you really want a discourse
关于时间平移相对论的长篇大论吗
in comparative theory of time displacement?
你能概括一下吗
Can you summarize?
冷冻室的那个人不是你  迈可
That's not you in the cryo chamber, Mac.
你就是你
You are you.
我不是  我是埃文创造的我
No, I'm not. I'm Evan's me,
是那个被他带离了
The version he created
自己的那个人生  带到这里
when he pulled me out of that life
而创造出的我
and brought me here.
跟我来
Well, come on.
什么
What?
去哪儿
Where?
别瞎看
Keep your eyes to yourself.
霍华德
Howard?
你这样生活多久了
How long have you been living like this?
怎样生活
Like what?
靠垃圾食品过活
Like a... junk food survivalist?
尽量减少消遣
Minimizing my distraction
我才能专注于新发明
so I can focus on my next innovation.
谐频方面的
In harmonics?
我带你来不是为了让你剽窃更多的专利
I didn't bring you in here so you could steal more patents.
我也没想剽窃
All right, that makes two of us.
你所谓的证据在哪里
So what's your so-called proof?
看到没
See?
可行的  光电
Operational... photonics.
当初我已经在决定生产规格了
I was working on the manufacturing specs
你却突然冒了出来
when you came out of nowhere.
三个月内快速上马
Geared up in three months,
在所有人反应过来之前
cornered the worldwide market
就已经垄断了全球市场
before anyone knew what happened.
生意如战场
It's just business.
很多人都在做同类的研究
A lot of people were doing parallel research.
是啊
Yeah.
没错  有这个可能
Sure, maybe.
而你恰好就取得了突破性进展
And you just happened to have the breakthrough.
是的  确实
Yeah. I did.
那超导体不稳定的问题呢
And the fact that you couldn't use a uniform superconductor?
这一点你是怎么解决的
How did you solve that one?
用纳米导线如何
The nanowire?
然后在外表镀上一层金
Coated that with gold.
这个办法的确巧妙
That's a cute trick.
我的团队对每一种可能都做了生产检测
But I had teams running manufacturing tests on every option.
历经了20个月的试验
After 20 months of trials,
我们终于把范围缩小到一种解决方案上
we were finally narrowing in on a solution,
结果一声霹雳
And boom!
埃文・克劳斯凭空出现
Evan Cross comes in out of nowhere,
不经任何实验就直接投入生产
and you go into production without one single trial?
这你怎么解释
How do you explain that?
我没必要解释
I don't have to explain it.
-去查我的专利文件  -我查了
- Check my patents... - I did!
它恰好说明你了解准确的方法
And what it shows is that you knew the right answer.
从一开始就知道
Right from the beginning,
完全没有人力投入
no sweat equity at all.
难不成  是你梦到的吗
So... It come to you in a dream?
不是不可能
It happens.
对  不是不可能  本来无可厚非
Yes, it does. Most definitely.
问题是
But here's the thing.
如果你真那么聪明
If you're that brilliant,
是个了不起的天才
if you're that much of a genius,
这种巧合会接二连三
it would happen again and again.
但那之后
And since then...
却再无成就
nothing.
我没法理解
I don't understand.
要么你就是剽窃
Either you're a patent thief...
要么过去五年你所做的事情
or whatever you've been working on for the last five years
重要到
is so big you're keeping it...
得秘而不宣
what, under wraps?
也许只是天不遂人愿
Or maybe things just didn't go as expected.
是不是只有一线之差
There's a bright line, isn't there?
然后物是人非
Between then and now.
本来满怀希望
Between everything's so full of promise...
转眼一切都黯淡无光
and everything's whole dark.
霍华德
Howard?
你是怎么了
What happened to you?
你有这么大的宅子
You've got this huge house,
自己却窝在这里
and you're holed up in here,
心有不甘
obsessing over what went wrong.
也许只是
Maybe things...
天不遂人愿
just didn't go as I expected.
埃文
Evan.
我在外边的游泳池旁
I'm out by the pool.
你得过来看看这个
You've got to see this.
失陪
Excuse me.
我得去看看我朋友
I have to check on my friend.
观察鸟的那位
The birdwatcher?
我以为你会告诉我
I've thought you're gonna tell me
她究竟是在找什么
what she's actually looking for?
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
如果他不在这儿
If this wasn't here,
即使埃文告诉你  你会相信他吗
would you have believed Evan even if he did tell you?
你是说他为了我才保守秘密
You're saying he kept it for me?
我不知道
I don't know.
不过如果他打算永远保守这个秘密
But, I mean, if he planned on keeping this a secret forever,
收藏着你的尸体可是很愚蠢的
then storing your body was a pretty stupid move,
埃文・克劳斯可不蠢
and Evan Cross isn't stupid.
他偷走了我的人生
He stole my life.
他救了你的命
He saved your life,
他还准备好要以死相救
and he was ready to die to do it.
仔细想一想
Think about it.
他改变你未来的那一刻
The moment he changed your future,
他一定知道未来的你没办法
He must have known that your future self wouldn't be there
阻止恐龙杀了他
to stop him from getting killed by a dinosaur.
如果当初不是我救他  他怎么还活着
So if I wasn't there to save him, why isn't he dead?
我不知道
I don't know.
而且我也不在乎
And you know what, I don't care,
因为你俩都活着
because you're both alive,
如果他这么做才有的这个结果
and if what he did is responsible for that,
那我很高兴他那么做了
then I'm glad that he did it.
因为众多选择里
Because of the choices available,
这个显然是最好的
this one's a hell of a lot more fun.
那你认为那个我是从何而来
So where do you suppose "I" came from?
明显是从某个异常点里来的
Out of an anomaly, apparently.
那一定是我以前的工作
So that must have been my job then.
拯救生命
Saving people?
我是说我穿着制服呢
I mean, I'm wearing a uniform.
迈可  那些实在是无从得知了
That's not really that much to go on, Mac.
这里的每个人似乎都认为你很聪明
Everyone around here seems to think you're pretty clever.
我打赌只要你花点心思就能搞清楚
I'll bet you could figure out what that arc symbol means
那个圆弧标志的意思了
if you put your mind to it.
我也许会考虑帮你
I might consider helping you.
只要你帮我过了三角龙那一关
But only if you help me put the triceratops back in the bottle.
我也许有办法
Well, I might have an idea about that.
看看我发现了什么
Look at what I found.
很好
Great.
我们只要弄清楚它要去哪就行了
Now we just need to find out where it goes.
交给我了
I've got this.
你去找异常点吧
You get that.
那个疯子呢
Where's crazy eyes?
在屋里
Inside...
抱着悔恨  颓废不堪
with his powerbars and regret.
它是不是美得难以置信
Isn't it magnificent?
真没想能有机会好好地观察恐龙
I've never had a chance to just sit and watch one.
埃文  别这样
Evan, come on.
不是所有恐龙都杀人不眨眼
They're not all vicious killers.
这一只没有危害
This one doesn't mean any harm.
它只是
He's just...
来错了地方  仅此而已
out of place, is all.
怎么说它都挺危险
It's still dangerous.
看看它
Look at it.
体形比大象还大
The thing's bigger than an elephant,
还有那些角  像矛一样
and those horns, they're like spears.
更别提如果有人看到它
Not to mention the little problem we'd have
我们要怎么解释了
trying to explain it if someone else sees it.
别开枪
Wait.
我们不想会搬着它走的
We don't want to have to carry it.
快跑
Move!
这还真是一只硕大无比的隐居鸫啊
That's one hell of a hermit thrush.
就是这个  对吧
That's it, right?
就是这个了
I mean, this is it!
这就是过去五年来你一直
This is the big secret that you've been working on
在隐藏的秘密  对吗
for the last five years, right?
我猜对了吧
Am I right?
伟大的埃文・克劳斯的重大突破
The great breakthrough by the great Evan Cross!
不完全是
Not exactly.
这太令人震惊了
This is huge!
你又不是遗传工程学家  我的朋友
I mean, you're no genetic engineer, my friend,
也就是说那东西是来自于
which means that thing came...
遥远的过去
from a distant past.
我就知道你们有所隐瞒  对吧
I mean, I knew you guys were hiding something, right?
对吧  但是三角龙
Right, but triceratops?
太意外了
That wasn't even on the list!
我喜欢惊喜
And I love surprises!
它要是不危险  刚刚是怎么回事
What happened to that thing not meaning any harm?
我们一定是吓到它了
We must've frightened it.
或者它以为游泳池是它的家
Or else it thinks the pool is its home,
它不过是在守卫自己的领地
and it was just defending its territory.
我会找到它
I'll find it.
你去找异常点
You find the anomaly.
找异常点
Find the anomaly...
坏了吗
Is it dead?
是啊  可能需要抢救一下
Yeah, it might need a little CPR.
需要帮忙吗
Need help?
我回来了
I'm back.
这东西你从哪里弄到的
Where did you get it?
我做的
I built it.
不可能  它太精密了
No, it's way too sophisticated.
这是我的得意之作
It's a pet project.
你想让我相信
You want me to believe
你发现了穿越时空之门
that you found doorways through time,
但你这个惊人的秘密成果
and yet your breakthrough secret project
不是你从未来世界带来的吗
isn't something from the future?
没准是偷来的
Maybe stolen?
没准是从未来的我手里偷的
Maybe from my future?
没准是我自己手里呢
Or mine?
你直到这意味着什么吗
Do you realize the implications of that?
这验证了费恩曼关于
Confirmation of Feynman's postulate
美国著名物理学家
时间线分支的假说
of branching timelines.
这验证不了任何事
Look, nothing's been confirmed.
也不能作为你上法庭的证据
And this isn't going to help your case in court.
别提上庭了
Oh, forget court!
这个能拿诺贝尔奖
This is Nobel territory!
甚至超越了诺贝尔奖
Beyond Nobel territory!
霍华德  不行
Howard, no.
这个消息不能走漏
None of it can leave this room.
你开玩...
Are you k--
绝对不行
None of it.
好  你想要我三缄其口吗
Okay, you want my silence?
把真相告诉我
Tell me the truth.
别装了
Come on!
你保守这秘密一定很辛苦
This has got to be killing you!
你一定迫切想找个能理解你的人
You have to be desperate for someone to talk to
一吐为快
who can actually understand.
不  没有
No. Not really.
埃文
Evan...
知道这种事不能给予你力量
Knowledge like this isn't power.
而是孤立无援
It's isolation.
好的  南斯小姐
Yes, Miss Nance,
我保证向他传达你说的话
I'll be sure he gets the message.
请问是"三角龙"吗
Now, was that "Triceratops" with one "r?"
喂
Hello?
出来
迈可  你不是说会帮我的吗
Mac, I thought you were going to help me.
言出必行
And so I have.
这是什么东西
What the hell?
它叫尖尖
His name's Spikey.
你在这儿啊
There you are.
这次慢慢来
Slowly this time.
看见没
Yeah, see?
没什么好担心的
There's nothing to worry about.
你这是怎么了
What is going on with you?
你不能觉得这全都是你的地盘吧
You can't think all of this is your territory.
是因为红色
It's the red.
你以为我是敌人
You think I'm a rival.
我们再试一次
Let's try this again.
你只是被吓到了
You're just scared.
也难怪
Why wouldn't you be?
我只是要确保
I'm just going to make sure
你不会再惹上麻烦
you don't get into any more trouble.
这东西废了
This is fried.
要是我就会安个限幅器防止超负荷
I'd have put in a limiter to stop it from overloading.
是吗
Oh, really?
谢谢你的建议
Well, thanks for the advice.
你有这个吗
Do you have anything?
有
Yeah.
我可以给你替换的零件
Yeah, I've got something you could kludge in there.
让磁力计重新工作
Get it up and running.
但我有个条件
For a price.
这不是在开玩笑  霍华德
This isn't a joke, howard.
没开玩笑  这我明白
No, I get that.
事关时空的连续性
This is the space-time continuum.
有毁灭世界的可能
It has world-ending potential,
而你不想成为
and you don't want to be
下一个奥本海默
the next Oppenheimer.
原子弹之父
没错
Exactly.
那你为什么要掺和这事呢
So why are you messing with it?
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
也许这些异常点很危险
As dangerous as these anomalies may be,
但还是把这些生物送回去的唯一途径
it's the only thing we have to put these creatures back.
你穿越过异常点吗
Have you ever been through one?
到另一个时空吗
To the other side?
是的
Yeah.
有过一两次
Once or twice.
那
And...
是不是很不可思议
was it amazing?
还很可怕
And frightening.
听着  我只是想把一切
Look, the only thing I'm trying to do
都送回原本属于的地方
is keep every single thing where it belongs.
你怎么管起这事了
How did that get to be your job?
记得你说的那句一线之差
You know that bright line you talked about
物是人非吗
between then and now?
我妻子被恐龙杀害的时候
That happened for me
也是一线之差
when a dinosaur killed my wife.
我能理解
I get that.
我妻子去世后
When my wife died...
如果我也能像你一样扛着步枪
if I could have gone after ovarian cancer
就能消灭卵巢癌
with your rifles...
我也会的
I would have.
埃文
Evan.
狄伦  你还好吧
Dylan. You all right?
不仅是还好
Better than all right.
还抓了只恐龙
I got me a dinosaur.
在哪儿
Where?
网球场
Tennis court.
我把它围在栅栏里了
The creature's fenced in,
当然它要是想逃跑栅栏也阻止不了
not that that'll matter if it decides to take off.
但我会去给它找些水和吃的
But I'm going to find it some food and water,
让它平静下来
get it to hunker down.
异常点探测器还有多久能弄好
How long till we've got an anomaly detector?
我们还在努力修
We're working on it.
动作快点
Work faster.
我得找到能塞满一校车的食物才够
I've gotta find enough food to fill a school bus.
收到
Roger that.
我得赶紧把这东西修好
I have to get this thing finished.
我们得在异常点关闭之前
We have to put that triceratops back through that anomaly
把三角龙送回去
before it closes.
还有多少时间
How long do you have?
不知道
No idea.
你不知道
You don't know?
我没有计时器
I don't have a timer.
我一直试着做一个  但是
I've been working on one, but--
埃文  我可以帮你
Evan, I can help.
要是你我联手
You and I working together,
没有什么解决不了的
there's very little we can't solve.
我想加入
I want in.
很好
Perfect.
我想我知道你喜欢吃什么
And I think I know what you like to eat.
它大约二十英尺高
It was, like, 20 feet tall,
有着巨大结实的角
with these big, massive horns,
还有...它在那儿
and-- there it is!
恐龙在那儿
There's the dinosaur!
不是吧
Oh no.
住手
Hey! Stop!
你们在干什么
What the hell are you doing?
狄伦  我不知道你已经在这里了
Dylan, I hadn't realized you were already on the scene.
我们在呢
Well, we are,
而且我已控制住了局势
and I have everything under control
让这些人走开好吗
if you'll just get these people to back off.
好吧  放下武器
Uh, yeah, uh, lower your weapons.
退后
And, um, pull back.
我是来帮忙的
I'm here to help.
但你是在帮倒忙  知道吗
Yeah, well, you're not helping, okay?
你要是在这里将它麻醉
If you tranq that thing here,
我们就得把它拉到异常点去
we're going to have to drag it all the way to the anomaly,
告诉你吧  我有经验
which, let me tell you from experience,
那比你想象的要难很多
is harder than you think.
我有一辆卡车
Yeah, I have a truck.
那不是重点
That's not the point.
这是一只温驯的动物
This is a docile animal,
它完全可以自己走回去
and it can move under its own power.
了解
Understood.
我以为托比让你
I thought that Toby sent you
去了滑板公园
to the skate park.
实况卫星图像显示了
Yeah, real-time satellite imagery revealed
这一带有巨大的流动热能
a remarkably large mobile heat signature on this property.
我是来
I'm here to offer
全力支持你的野外行动
full operational coordination with your field efforts.
我们目标一致
We are on the same team.
那我有个适合你的任务
Then I have just the job for you.
那道门
The portals,
你称之为异常点  是吧
you call them anomalies, right?
是的
Yeah.
你喜欢吗
You like that?
当然
Sure.
你认为这是它们的工作原理
Then this is your theory on how they work.
对  出现  磁场波动
Yeah, they appear, they fluctuate,
然后消失
they disappear.
有一定的规律
There's a pattern to it,
但每次都不一样
but it's different every single time.
我还没有算出
I haven't been able to figure out
它的傅里叶级数[一种特殊的三角级数]
the fourier series for it yet.
那是因为你的方向错了
That's because you're going about it wrong.
你想找到消失在混乱中的常量
You're trying to find a value lost in chaos.
但那是无法预测的
That can't be predicted.
说明白点
Elaborate on that.
如果它与重叠的正弦波无关呢
What if it's not about overlapping sine waves?
如果...
What...
让我解释清楚
Let me explain.
异常点  它们带有磁性  对吧
The anomalies, they're magnetic, right?
因此每次出现时
So every time they appear,
都会产生独一无二的磁特性
there's going to be a unique signature
因为它们会和地球磁场
caused by an interference
相互干扰
with the earth's magnetic field.
那就对了
Done.
所以你要预测的不是一个规律
So it's not a pattern you're trying to predict.
没错  是一条磁特性谐波
Of course. It's a harmonic signature.
对
Right.
我该测量的
It's not the standing field
不是固定磁场
I should be trying to measure.
而是初始磁力
It's the initial event.
就像一枚逐渐减弱的音符
It's like a musical note that fades.
对  当它减弱到临界点时
Yes, and when it decays past the critical threshold...
异常点就会关闭
The anomaly collapses.
完全正确
Exactly.
可以预测
Predictably.
那么我们需要做的
So all we need to do
就是将一个晶体悬空于基液之中
is suspend a crystal in a fluid matrix.
我们没有那么多时间
We don't have time for that.
我必须找到这个异常点
I have to find the anomaly.
但谢谢你  霍华德
But thank you, Howard.
谢谢
Thank you.
放那里
Just there.
等等
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
你们这些人是在干什么
What the hell do you people think you're doing?
对不起  女士
I'm sorry, ma'am.
我有官方授权
I have official authorization
征用这些花朵
to commandeer these flowers
出于国家安全的原因
for reasons of national security.
但这些花我获过奖
But they're my prize-winning flowers!
是的  它们的确很美
Yes, I understand that they're beautiful--
各位  那些...
Gentlemen, that's--
那些够用了  谢谢  好极了
That's plenty. Thanks, great.
是的  就是...
Yup. Just...
女士  在这个混乱的年代
In these uncertain times, ma'am,
为了自由  我们都要有所牺牲
we all have to make sacrifices for freedom.
您今天漂亮极了
You look lovely today.
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness...
走
Go.
你觉得这样行吗
You think this will work?
比食物更有诱惑力的就只有性了
The only better lure than food is sex.
所言甚是
Yeah, truer words.
埃文一告诉我们异常点所在地
When Evan tells us where to go,
我们就很慢很温柔地  引它回去
we'll just walk it back, nice and slow.
没必要搞得那么刺激
There's no need for all that excitement.
这次终于不需要了
For once.
我的天啊
My god...
看哪
Look at--
霍华德  别太靠近
Howard, don't get too close.
看看碎片层
Look at the shard layer.
那是时空的边缘
It's the edge of space and time
被炸得四分五裂
just blown apart.
我想是因为
I think it's from the impact
四维表面的相互碰撞
of colliding four-dimensional surfaces.
它可能只是
I think it might just be
被人类肉眼看到的样子  但...
the way the human eye perceives it, but...
真美
it is beautiful.
是啊
Yeah...
这就是过去和现在的
It's the bright line
一线之差
between then and now.
可以让我来吗
May I?
好的
It's okay.
你的计时器  先生
Your timer, sir.
你怎么这么快就做好了
How did you make that so quickly?
我只是在我花了一年多时间
I just tweaked a resonator
研究的共振仪上稍做改动
I've been working on for over a year.
简直像是宿命一般
It's almost like it was destiny.
成功了
And it works.
我们只剩不到两分钟了
And we have less than two minutes.
两分钟  你确定吗
Two minutes? You're sure?
一分五十秒
A minute and 50 seconds.
假如这东西精确的话
Assuming this thing is accurate.
计算误差大约在十万分之六上下
The calculated margin for error is .006%, give or take.
你在哪里
Where are you?
保龄球场往东两百米
Uh, 200 metres east of the Bowling Green.
我九十秒后到达
Be there in 90 seconds.
你干什么  你要去哪里
What are you doing? Where are you going?
去异常点  没时间解释了
Anomaly. No time to explain.
我能帮你什么吗
How can I assist?
快闪开  小龙要回家了
Get out of the way. This baby's going home!
这是在模仿斗牛士的斗篷吗
Is this analogous to a bullfighter's cape?
其实公牛是色盲
Because bulls are colour-blind.
他们更容易被...
They're more attracted to--
闭嘴
Shut...up.
埃文
Evan!
只剩十五秒了
It's 15 seconds.
她赶不过来的
She's not gonna make it.
她会赶上的
She will.
小心
Look out!
-还有几秒钟时间  -你还好吗
- And with seconds to spare. - You okay?
霍华德
Howard--
再见了
Goodbye.
那人是谁
Who was that?
他来多久了
How long has he been here?
友善点
Be nice.
他为给大家伙找吃的出了不少力
He was very helpful getting fodder for the big guy.
刚刚那个男人  他去哪儿了
There was a man here. Where did he go?
他是霍华德・凯纳恩  你知道他去了哪
It was Howard Kanan. And you know where he went.
这情况有意思
Interesting development.
他为什么那么做
Why would he do that?
不知道
I don't know.
出于好奇  自负  或愚蠢至极
Curiosity? Arrogance? Complete stupidity?
还是三者皆有
Or all of the above.
他在那边会没命的
He's going to die in there.
也许更糟
Or worse.
多谢了  迈可
Thanks, Mac.
你帮了我大忙
You really saved my ass.
帮了大家的大忙
All of our asses, really.
我是看在你的面子上[双关:翘臀]才帮忙的
Well, it was your ass that I did it for.
不想换个说法吗
You might want to rephrase that.
不了
Um... no.
这事别告诉埃文
Don't tell Evan about this.
为什么
Why?
我要先弄清楚一些事
I need to get some answers first.
少不了要你帮忙
With your help.
好吧  就按我们说好的
Okay, a deal's a deal.
不过我要说
But I will say that it's...
这里少了你感觉怪怪的
it's not the same here without you.
而且
And...
老天  没想到我要说这种话
Oh, my god, I can't believe I'm saying this.
我想你
I miss you.
那就帮个忙  常来看看我
Then do me a favor and visit me from time to time.
"我"在冷冻室里肯定很孤单
I must get lonely down there in the freezer.
想着你会常去看看  我就放心了
I'd like to think you were checking up on me.
就这么定了
Deal.
托比  这是什么玩意
Toby, what the hell's this?
这是...
Oh, it's, uh...
只是...
It's just that...
不要紧
Never mind.
网上的消息你封锁了吗
You get the internet shut down?
其实我想到了更好的办法
Actually, I did better than that.
让人为之一笑的是
...and on the lighter side,
一场精心策划的恐龙骗局今天风靡网络
an elaborate dinosaur hoax swept the internet today
当前播放: 骇人真恐龙实为恶作剧
此事始于本地滑板公园的一个恶作剧
following a prank at a local skate park.
在那儿  恐龙在那儿
There it is! There's the dinosaur!
请谨记  如果有人给了你一段
So remember, if somebody shows you footage
"骇人真恐龙"的视频
of a freaking real dinosaur,
要三思而后信
think twice before you believe it.
交给你了  山姆
Over to you, Sam.
干得好
Nice.
是啊  我觉得这不会是最后一次
Yeah, well, I figured it's not the last time
有人抓拍到恐龙  对吧
someone's gonna get a video of a dinosaur, right?
所以不如就让人们认为那全都是恶作剧
So might as well make them all seem fake.
你叫了迈可来帮忙
You called Mac in.
算是吧
Um... Sort of.
不过你说得对
But, uh, you were right.
他还需要点时间
He's gonna need some time.
干得好
Good work.
再给我放一遍那个报道
Hey, show me that thing one more time.
好
Yes.
巨大的角  而且
...massive horns, and...
在那儿  恐龙在那
There it is! There's the dinosaur!
有我的电话吗
Any calls?
只有霍尔上校打来
Just Colonel Hall.
他想知道最新进展
He'd like an update.
真不错
Oh, terrific.
你有烦心事
Something's bugging you.
我会变成那样吗
Is that where I'm headed?
我会是下一个
Am I the next crazy eyes
住在庄园里的科学怪人吗
living alone in a mansion somewhere?
你是因为迈可才走上这条路的吗
You going down this road because of Mac?
你知道他会回来的  对吗
You know he'll be back, right?
其实我是在想磁力计
I was thinking about this, actually.
我在这项技术上倾注了三年心血
Three years I've been working on this tech,
以为它能解决一切问题
thinking it would solve everything.
弥补一切遗憾
Make up for everything.
修正一切错误
Fix everything.
但如果它办不到呢
But what if it doesn't, hmm?
我第一次见到你时
The first time I saw you,
你手里就拿着个磁力计
you had one of those things in your hands.
你目不转睛地看着它
You couldn't keep your eyes off it.
我以为你是在用九十年代的大哥大呢
I thought you'd kept your phone from the 90's or something.
是啊  我总是给人留下良好的第一印象
Yeah, well, I always make a good first impression.
但这东西
But that thing,
今天送了我一份大礼
it gave me a gift today.
我一直...
I've, uh...
我一直在为这份工作纠结
I've been really struggling with this work,
因为这和猛兽控制队不一样
because it isn't like predator control.
猛兽控制队对付的大都是无害的动物
This isn't mostly harmless animals
偶尔才有杀人的猛兽
with the occasional killer.
这些生物却大都杀人不眨眼
These creatures are almost all killers.
今天我们终于遇到一只无害的恐龙
But today we finally had one that wasn't.
我们要做的就是把它送回家
And all we had to do was show it the way home,
而我们做到了
and we did that.
我们做到了
We did it.
你对这些生物有着
You have a feel for these things
我所没有的感情
that I don't have.
我甚至不确定我是否曾经有过
I'm not sure if I'll ever have it.
以前在家我常常得在周围绕上铁丝网
I used to coil razor wire back home.
因为经常有狼从森林里跑出来
We had wolves that would come down out of the forest
捕食我们养的羊
and try to eat our sheep.
爸爸说我们得挡住它们
My dad said we had to keep them out,
但是每过一个月左右
but every month or so,
我走到铁丝网外总能看到
I would come out, and I would f-find...
那些狼会被铁丝网缠住
They would get tangled in the wire sometimes.
为了求生它们会把爪子咬断
They'd chew their own paws off.
从那时起我就明白了
That's really when I got it, you know?
那不是它们的错  对吗
It isn't their fault, right?
那只是它们的本能
They're just being who they are.
问题在我们身上
We're the problem.
是人类想主宰一切
We're the ones who want everything to be human.
我们已经给整个世界围上了层层铁网
Now we've covered the whole damn world in razor wire.
而那些...
So where are...
那些动物要在何处安家呢
Where are the animals supposed to go?
但是今天
But today,
你想出了一个良策帮助它们
you came up with a better way to help them.
就是把它们送回那个没有人类的时代
To get them back to a time with no humans in it.
霍华德弄的那个零件
Hey, that thing that Howard made,
你还能弄出来吗
you can make that again?
那就去做吧
Then do it.
这项技术不只是为了帮助你
The tech isn't just to help you.
是为了帮助它们
It's to help them.
我们能做的也只有这些了  对吗
It's the least we can do, right?
形势所迫目标任务没有完成  长官
The mission objective was compromised by circumstances, sir.
但好的一面是
But on the positive side,
标本回到了它的自然栖息地
the specimen was returned to its natural habitat.
还有个有意思的新情况
And there was an interesting, um, development.
我会在报告中写明
I'll have that in my report.
是的  长官  不言而喻
Uh, yes, sir, that goes without saying.
我们目标一致
We are on the same team.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.